A covered put would be
considered by someone
who would like to
derive additional income
from a short stock position.
A covered put allows
the investor to
hold a short equity
position while
simultaneously receiving
the premium from
selling an equal amount of
put options against it.
The covered put writer is bearish
on the stocks
long-term potential,
but is willing to forego
a stock's downside below
the strike during the
life of the option,
in order to receive the
proceeds of the put premium.
The covered put writer
benefits from time decay,
from a reduction in volatility,
and if the stock decreases
its dividend before expiration.
It should be noted that
the combined position has
a similar profile to
that of a short call.
The covered put writer remains
exposed to any upside in
the underlying shares,
meaning his loss
potential is unlimited.